It's high noon in old Cheyenne. So, I'd
like to call the February uh meeting
April
way behind, huh?
February showers bring March flowers.
April
7th meeting of the Finance Committee to
order.
Uh if you're in the audience, be sure
you have your cell phones on vibrate or
muted.
Uh online, uh use the raise hand
function and we'll let you in to speak.
And uh
approach the podium.
Turn on the light.
Uh all communications will go through
the chair. With that,
first item.
Number 10A, application for a bar and
grill liquor license filed with the city
clerk's office for Mongolian Bar and
Grill doing business as Mongolian Bar
and Grill, 1637 Stillwater Avenue, Suite
C, Cheyenne, Wyoming. Mr. Stefferud.
Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
Kylie Sodun, City Clerk. The item before
you is an application for a bar and
grill liquor license for Mongolian Bar
and Grill LLC doing business as
Mongolian Bar and Grill. The application
has been reviewed by applicable city
departments and the Wyoming Liquor
Division and requirements for the
application have been met. And I am
happy to answer any questions you may
have and I believe the applicant is
present as well.
Comments or questions from the
committee? Mr. Stefferud. Mr. Chair,
just a for
uh clerk. How many uh bar and grills
will this leave remaining?
Mr. Chairman, through you to Councilman
White, after this one is awarded, there
will be five.
Thank you.
Uh seeing no more questions from the
committee, I'll go to public comment.
Anyone in the room want to comment on
this item?
How about online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion? Mr.
Chair, I move to approve. Second.
It's been moved by Councilman White,
second by Councilman Moon. Any further
discussions?
All in favor signify by saying aye.
Opposed, no.
Seeing that that's unanimous, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item,
please. Number 19, ordinance second
reading, appropriating money for the
Reed Avenue Corridor project.
Staff report.
Want to do it, Councilman LeBourne?
Good.
No. Okay.
Good afternoon, Chairman. Ask of all the
members of the Finance Committee. Yep.
Tom Cobb, City Engineer. Um hopefully
you are doing well. Sorry about the dog.
I I briefly wanted to go through sort of
a current update. I know some of you
have heard some of this, others have not
heard everything. Um
but uh if you can go to the second
slide, Jennifer, that'd be great.
I've got a little delay on my end. It's
not showing up very well. Just a second,
let me switch.
Okay.
So, I wanted to go through with a little
current status and where the project is
in the BNSF process. I think some of you
had seen this, but not all of you had.
Um I also wanted to briefly go on the
road closure, the criteria used, and
sort of the overview of those closures,
and the impacts that we would expect
with it closed and without it closed,
and decisions that were made in regard
to why they were closed. Um I also
wanted to go through a summary of the
current task and deliverables both from
our side and the clients,
which includes this 22905 agreement
that's required as part of our FRA
grant. And then I wanted to go through
some highlights from the meeting that we
had with the BNSF that included the
mayor and myself and the chief of staff.
Um
uh and then sort of from that, the
overview of the proposed project is sort
of the funding and if any questions you
might have. Next slide, please.
So, where we are in the process. So,
this diagram I laid out, I think it it
kind of illustrates sort of more more in
more detail of where we actually are in
the project. You know, from the project
concept is on the left as you move to
the right is through their process. We
had the P&E services agreement that we
executed with them. We had the plan
submittal for the 30%. And right now,
we're in terms with the 22905 agreement.
I think right now we'll get that
submitted then and approved. BNSF has
already approved the 22905.
And then we'll move we're working now
with our consultant as they are working
on the 60% plan and that submittal to
the railroad. And as you move to the
right, you can see there are two more
agreements that we really have to get or
one more agreement that we have to get
before we actually get to construction.
And that's that construction and
maintenance agreement. And that's those
terms then will be established at that
time. And I'll go into that in a little
bit, but we do have to pay a small fee
that we've now under understand from our
meeting from BNSF to actually use the
corridor for for our project. And then
we get final BNSF approval and then then
on to construction. Next slide, please,
Jennifer.
So, the criteria we used for the
closures
So, the number of an access and crossing
closures obviously, and I've said this
before, but I want to make sure it's
really clear, the the number and the
closures was determined by BNSF.
They can They're the controlling juris-
jurisdiction for the rail corridor
itself. Obviously, we gave up that in
about 1908, a a former city council that
did that. Specific closure locations
were identified using the Cheyenne MPO
traffic demand model, and that evaluates
both the existing traffic conditions,
and then we look at the projected 2050
average daily volume traffics, and
that's based on anticipated regional
development, which are the generators,
and then also, we've got network
closures that we know are going to
happen in that time frame. What's the
potential closure of 24th Street from
Central Avenue to Pioneer, as requested
by the legislature, and I've got Capital
Avenue from 24th to 23rd. Both those
elements were included in the MPO model
to so we can see what traffic would do
when we do close those roads. Next
slide, please.
So, this diagram illustrates, and I
tried to not make it too complicated,
but on the top, the numbers in blue are
where they are today. That's the average
daily traffic. And you can see what the
orange circles are the proposed
closures, which are 17th, 18th, 21st,
and then Dillon. So, if you look at the
top, the reason those particular streets
were chosen is by the lowest ADT on the
corridor. And obviously, as we've talked
about before, we waited until the very
last moment at the request by BNSF for
that fourth closure, which was 21st
Street. Even though it had the smallest
ADT, we understood the development that
was going on in the surrounding area,
and we didn't want to do it because of
the investment to to corridor. So, you
can see as you look through, it's it's
pretty plain and ordinary, but there's
also the impacts at the end. You can see
what I done as you work down the list,
blue is what it is today.
Then, in the green is with the 2050 ADT
without the closures. And I What I mean
is the closures for 24th Street and
Capital. And then, the last is the the
red is with the closures of those
outside streets.
Next slide, please.
So, this is kind of an overview of the
corridors. And and you know, if you
looked uh what I want to illustrate with
this one is that Lincoln Way, 19th, and
20th, and 22nd are really going to only
be the through streets that run all the
way over to Logan or further. And again,
it's critical why 22nd wasn't chosen as
a closure because it will only be the
last remaining through street to Logan.
If we were to do that backwards, um
it obviously we we wouldn't have that
connectivity.
Next slide, please.
So, a summary of the current task and
deliverables. So, our DHM design team is
working on the 60% design development
and updating the engineers cost estimate
for construction.
Um as I stated before, the they are in
they're preparation right now. They're
modifying a contract modification that
will come before all of you um hopefully
on the next cycle. Um I do have and I'll
show you with the money wise. And what I
did with that is I included to add scope
for going ahead and doing the boundary
streets on 17th, 18th, 19th, 21st, and
22nd Street. And really, what I began to
look at all this, uh the original scope
didn't include the side streets that
were adjacent to the corridor. And to
me, it made sense for pedestrian
connectivity that we go ahead and update
those streets as we're as we're in this
area. And that would be used from a
separate funding store so a separate
funding source, which is the 1% fifth
penny.
We're still looking at a public meeting
in the preparation of that planning
document that for the 60% somewhere this
summer, we hope to get that out to all
of the public. Um we're still continuing
property owner and business owner
one-on-one meetings as required.
And then from the city of Cheyenne's
team, um
we're obviously still facilitating the
purchase of a portion of the Wyman
lottery property, which most of you have
seen. That's that north lot um adjacent
to them on the west side of the
corridor.
We're continuing to explore
opportunities to secure grants and other
funding opportunities, and then we're
looking at the execution of that FRA
22905 agreement, which obviously is the
crossing elimination grant.
Um we are we as I we facilitated a
coordinating meeting with the mayor. Um
unfortunately, we weren't able to get
all the council people of Ward 1
available at that time, but that meeting
I'll I'll go into more detail with that.
And then again, the property owner and
business owner one-on-one meetings as
necessary. Next slide, please.
From the BSA BNSF team's perspective, um
that coordination meeting um was held um
again with Mayor Collins, the chief of
staff, and myself and and the design
team. Um
and we then now from their perspective,
as I've said before, they've already
DocuSign the FRA 22905 agreement, and
I'll go into that what actually that
some of those terms of that agreement
are.
From the FRA's perspective, they're
waiting for our execution of the 22905,
and then they'll award the project. Next
slide, please.
So, the 2290905 agreement and really the
purpose of that agreement is to provide
the federal government with the required
assurances for the FRI railroad crossing
crossing elimination grant, and it
really says that the railroad supports
what we're doing and moving forward.
That's what the document is about. It in
detail, you know, from our side, the the
scope itself is is outlined in the
agreement. It says we're going to remove
four accurate crossings. We're going to
upgrade six additional crossings with
new safety devices. We're going to
install quarter fencing to prevent
unauthorized access and obviously we're
adding storm drainage improvements. The
key assurances from the side is the city
will compensate BNSF for the right away
use which we talked about and we since
then after we talked to the design team,
we believe that this one-time payment in
which I'm now getting a an appraisal
for. We have to praise that the ground
that we're going to use and basically
it'll be about 10% of the property value
and it at the most right now what I
calculated based on other appraisals in
the area that we had done is is roughly
$200,000
and we'll get that we'll get that
figured out as we move through but
that's the maximum and it's a one-time
payment for the life of the use.
The agreement whoops, sorry Jennifer.
Can you go back one more time?
It This agreement doesn't obligate
either party to proceed with
construction. As I said, that has to be
a separate agreement with the
construction and maintenance agreement
and then further negotiations we're
going to need as with those agreements
as we move forward.
Okay, thank you. Next one.
So, I what I wanted to talk about in
this slide is basically the meeting that
took place between the mayor and BNSF
and myself and the design team. Um what
it did is provide a forum for direct
productive dialogue between the city
leadership and BNSF.
Um from the city of Cheyenne's
perspective and our project purpose as I
said is to reimagine the Reed Avenue
rail corridor as an economic catalyst
for the west edge. We want to improve
that public safety um with enhanced
safety measures and drainage upgrades
and we really want to support
reinvestment and a long-term economic
vitality for the adjacent businesses.
Some of the discussion points the mayor
had with the team or with the BNSF team
rather is that the fourth closure
requirement presents significant impact
to to those local businesses that
they've invested the money so far and
the and the potential for the future
ones to do so.
And the mayor did request they
reconsider the fourth closure and of
course I will go on with the next slide
from their perspective that does not fit
their model.
From the BNSF perspective, their primary
considerations overall are the safety
operation and efficiency and maintenance
of of their railroad. Um that is their
core priority. And from their
perspective, redevelopment may restrict
future industrial use of the corridor
whereas in our perspective,
redevelopment it really is that economic
catalyst. So again, you see two
different sides of the story both trying
to get to a different means. And from
again from their perspective, when you
increase pedestrians and vehicles in any
manner, it presents a safety and
operational challenge for them.
And that redevelopment introduces that
from there from there, it's complete
exposure to liability. And therein lies
the difference between the two
perspectives.
So
the position of the road closures
obviously as I've discussed before, BNSF
views road closures as the as the only
method for improving safety and reducing
liability from their standpoint while
still permitting us to redevelop in the
corridor. So again, just two different
sides of the fence
but they want us to allow us to move
forward but the exchange is we have to
get these road closures for them to be
able to limit their liability. So from
the mutual benefit side for both of us,
when we upgrade the crossings and
enhance, we really enhance the overall
safety of both the corridor users and
the railroad operations. Those drainage
improvements then also reduce flooding
which improves safety from their
standpoint and and reliability for them
and then also for us.
And then finally, this is the point that
we finally got to at the end of the
meeting which was a game changer in my
mind. Basically, they understood then if
we we were talking about having no
pedestrian access on the west side, and
what the potential would be is we
introduce people trying to bypass, jump
over the fences at those areas that we
closed the crossing, because remember a
crossing is both for vehicles and
pedestrians. So, as it as they began to
look at it, they realized that we did
need
pedestrian connectivity on the west
side, so they are open then to allow an
8-ft If you go to the next slide,
Jennifer.
So, what I'm trying to show here is if
you look at the orange spaces, those
would be within the corridor itself
that's controlled by
the BNSF. If you look from left to right
on the section at the bottom, it
introduces now at least an 8-ft corridor
for pedestrians to then be able to get
to the areas that we don't have closed
crossings.
And this again is a game-changer both
from the business side on the other
side. We've now made the connection that
they wanted. We don't get vehicles, but
we do get pedestrians, so they can move
their folks into that primary promenade
for pedestrian corridor. Next slide,
please.
So, last but not least, the available
funding.
Obviously, as I've talked to before, the
Federal Railroad Administration grant is
about 3.4 million. That includes an
800,000 match on our side. Um, what's
remaining in the fund right now from the
6-penny is about 2.21 million for a
total of 5.62 million. What's going to
come out of what's remaining funds that
we do have,
um, is about a $350,000
change order from our consultant to do
those extended roadway components that
we have.
Um,
and I believe that's all I had. Next
slide, I think that's the end. Do you
have any questions you have for me? I
will take them at this time.
Okay, comments and questions from the
committee you Engineer Cobb.
Thank you, Councilman Moody. Hi. Thank
you, Mr. Chair, and through you. Uh
thank you, Mr. Cobb. I do have a couple
questions. Um for the traffic study,
have you included the new uh apartment
buildings that are going up?
Chairman Escobedo, through you to to
Councilman Moody. Yeah, yes, sir. We do
look at the model looks at redevelopment
um as a as a whole. Uh the model is
really it's a it's a 50,000-ft view, so
we look at many different types of
developments.
Oh, Mr. Chair, good. All right. Thank
you, Mr. Chair, and through you. Um
I know you've done studies on that. Have
you done any studies on potential uh
gen- uh potential gentrification at all
in this area?
Uh Chairman through you to to Councilman
Moody. Could you repeat the question,
sir? I'm sorry. I've got a little
background traffic noise.
No problem. Um have you uh has anybody
done any studies you're aware of of
potential gentrification in this area?
Uh uh Chairman through you to Councilman
Moody. Not that I'm aware of, sir.
Okay. One last question.
Uh thank you, Mr. Chair, and through
you. Um just uh curious. I says a city
with modern economic vision.
Um what does that mean? Cuz I know BNSF
says the industrial usage. What what
does it mean by modern economic value?
Uh Chairman Escobedo, through you to
Councilman Moody.
It was just revitalization and economic
driver. We're trying to get potential
for businesses adjacent to be able to
develop. That was that's all. There's
nothing nothing else.
I just a quick comment. Go ahead. Yeah,
just um just a little confused by that
cuz it is an industrial area. And you
know, when I think of that is maybe
revitalization of warehouses to ship out
cuz our freight has increased a lot here
in the United States in the past a
years, so just comment there. Thank you.
Any other questions from the committee?
Councilor Wolf.
Uh
thank you, Mr. Chairman. Uh through you,
um Mr. Cobb, thank you very much. Thank
you for taking your time. Uh we know
you're uh out of town and we appreciate
you
uh
calling in and also your incredible work
on this. Um
and um
I uh
I just want to I mean, there there's a
lot of
uh hopeful things happening on this part
of town. Um and I think some of that
goes to uh Councilwoman Moody's
um observation about gentrification. I
think it's going to take us a long time
to really gentrify that quarter, but uh
we've got um
things that are all um interrelated and
and this is a
absolutely a key aspect of that.
Um so, kind of looking at the timing, um
uh
department uh
had uh Cobb, what um what what what do
you think um
I I there there are a bunch of moving
parts here and and as uh if we can um
get um this um reserve allocated and get
the money available, what do you think
in terms of the timing of this uh moving
forward, particularly as it uh relates
to
um
dealing with that uh triangular piece
and and uh interest that's uh been
expressed in developing it?
Thank you. Go ahead, Engineer Cobb.
Um Chairman Esquivel, through you to to
Councilwoman Wolf. Um Mr. Wolf, I you
know, I don't have a firm schedule from
the consultant right now, but if I had
to take a guess, I would say we've got
about 6 months of of to finish the 60%
and above. Um
I think after that that review, based on
what BNSF has done to us in the past, I
mean, you could be you could be looking
at up to a 12-month period, but I don't
foresee that this time cuz I think we've
come to terms of where we are. I think
they're going to look at um this in a
different aspect now since we've had so
many different meetings with them. So
roughly I think we're about a year away
from a
a final design, sir.
Any further questions from the
committee?
Mr. Chairman, just one. Go ahead. Uh
thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um
I I guess one piece of uh
insight that I learned uh over the
weekend um
there'd been some concern um expressed
by particularly some of the investors
along the Reed Avenue corridor
about the Sites Rose property, which is
the Elevator and the Blossom um yoga
building and um
I actually learned this weekend that
that property's gone under contract. Um
and uh
so I don't know who the prospective uh
buyer is, but
um that um actually would look to be a
positive um development uh that that
property came up for sale and then
uh has already um found uh a buyer. So
we'll obviously have to wait and see
what the details of that are, but um
um maybe an indication that there
continues to be a lot of um
interest from uh investors in um that uh
buildings there and you know, uh
hopefully what uh
all of the people involved in this are
doing. Thank you.
Any other comments or questions from the
committee for Engineer Cobb?
Uh Engineer Cobb, do we get a car total
or
of uh how many
trains actually are using that track per
week or month or anything like that?
Chairman, um the only thing that we had
and and and I've got G McDonald
available as well. My memory serves it
in the summer it's it's about two a
month. It's it's not very active, sir.
And it's still 10 mile an hour track.
Chairman, yes, sir.
Uh we'll go to public comment now.
Councilman Labor.
Thank you, Mr. Excuse me. Thank you, Mr.
Chairman. Um
I'm not only speaking here as an
advocate of the project and a original
West Sider from my childhood,
but I am also the chairman of the Reed
Avenue Steering Committee.
And I just want to thank Engineer Cobb
for all he's done.
This has been a really, really unique
and difficult situation.
And one that uh
quite possibly could have fallen by the
wayside. Um it didn't.
And I think that's a definitely a credit
to us and to his department because
this really is a sixth penny project
from way back.
So, everything that he just explained
really details what the situation is and
how it's going to proceed.
So, now that we're in that
situation where we are in agreement with
the railroad,
uh it's a question of financing.
And you can see in the FRA grant the
money that's left over from the sixth
penny, that five million and change is
uh
if we add the five million dollars we're
talking about today,
you're in the neigh- you are in the
neighborhood of the ability to actually
do the project correctly.
And the reason to do the project
correctly
is that
these investors are local investors.
This isn't uh
This isn't some out-of-town uh effort
here. This is something that they
believe in and invest in because of they
live here
and that they care about it. So, I would
also like to point out that this is far
from a unique situation.
Everything that the city has been
driving to the west
for the past many years
has taken an disadvantaged neighborhood
and a
uh
business model
that changed. I mean, they they don't
deliver uh
products to those warehouses anymore off
that rail line. So, um
very difficult project a lot of effort
went into it
and I think that we're now ready to uh
seal the deal and proceed.
It's something that I think we'll all be
proud of. Thank you.
Any further public comment?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Chairman,
Council, great to see you. Uh Darren
Westby, 714 West 20th Street, uh right
on the Reed Rail Corridor. Um
I want to echo what the councilman said.
Uh
really want to applaud the staff's
efforts and the council's effort to keep
this moving forward. 6 years ago when
the family and I decided to buy that
property and
revitalization was it. That was the
whole reason. Um looking at the blighted
community that we had down here on the
West End, knowing that there was some
low-hanging fruit and that we could try
to be a part of it. We were excited to
be a part of it. And quite honestly, um
surprised uh how well it's going. I I
can't say to gentrification commissioner
uh
Councilman Moody
but I've seen a lot of improvements.
Um
old houses that had boarded up windows
and doors are now getting painted and
and new siding and new roof and mowed
grass and I'm seeing more residential to
the point where again, thank you to this
body. Um we have another opportunity to
make an improvement to our facility to
uh with the
uh residential growth with the apartment
and all the other residentials around us
have the ability to fulfill maybe a a
grocery desert that we have down here.
Obviously, we're not going to be a
Safeway,
but we're definitely looking at putting
in a we're calling it a bodega just to
be cool. But uh
but I think ultimate urban market, mini
market, whatever we can do to to provide
the essentials to the people that are
moving down there. We felt it. People
are walking to our facility now. Uh we
have a parking issue, but uh it's
lightened with the amount of people that
are walking to the facility now, which
is really amazing. Um
so, we're seeing the change that we 6
years ago
had as a vision and a drive that I've
listened to a lot of people that have
been in this room over the last 10 years
that this is the next thing. Well, we
jumped on it.
Um we're really uh we jumped on it
because there was a read rail plan. We
jumped on it because there was a 6-penny
uh initiative. We jumped on it because
there was actual passage of that.
A lot of planning, and I understand
being in my in my day job, there's a lot
of planning that goes into any projects,
and I'm really grateful for it, but it's
time to quit the plans, put some dirt uh
in a shovel, and get it to fruition. So,
really um appreciate the ordinance. Uh
really appreciate to see what's going to
happen uh with passage, um and really
excited within a year to see some dirt
being turned, and uh show the
improvements that can and should be done
down on the Swiss side. So, I'd be happy
to stand for any questions.
No questions?
Thank you, Darren. Thank you.
Any further public comment?
Welcome, sir.
Mr. Escobel, committee. Uh Tony Lucero,
ANC feeds, 721 West 22nd.
Uh ANC feeds been there since uh
1917. We've never left.
And uh I've only been there 49 years, so
but
I've kind of been around a little bit.
But uh we started when this whole thing
started with the Commons Park, and we
had a lot of trouble with Commons Park.
Took forever to get that going.
And uh this project started, and I went
to the first meeting, and I asked, I
don't remember who was at the meeting,
but I know Roybal was there.
And I asked,
"Is this project going to take as long
as this Commons Park did?" And they all
said, "Oh, no, no, no, it's not going to
take nearly as long." Well, it's taken
longer.
And uh I'm just really glad to see
something going on. We've We've waited
long enough. I think it's time we do
something. Thank you.
Yeah, Tony, I I dealt with the railroad
for 44 years, and they don't move
nothing fast.
Any uh further public comment?
How about online?
Can we get a motion?
Mr. Chair, I move to approve on second
reading. Second.
It's been moved by Councilwoman White,
seconded by Councilwoman Wolf. Any
further comments?
Councilwoman White. Uh Mr. Chair, I'm
just really happy to see something like
this come before us today. I know it's
been pointed out that this
uh particular project has seemed to have
taken much longer than any of us
thought. However, when
we first started the project, we
we really weren't aware that the city
council in 1908 had given away the
right-of-way on that Reed Avenue
corridor. So, that's probably one of the
the things that um
has delayed this the most. Um but I've
I've told many people uh
just recently since
this energy it seems to have been
renewed in this that we've never been
closer
to getting this over the goal line than
we are right now. The conversations with
the railroad have been very positive and
constructive. They've essentially given
us a verbal green light, which
I know for some folks that doesn't sound
like a big deal, but for those of us who
have had interactions
uh with projects that have to deal with
the railroad over the last 10 years I've
been on on council, it is huge. It's
it's really the linchpin
on whether or not things can proceed
forward or not. And we seem to be at
that point.
The um I also want to thank the
commitment of the investors and the
local business owners because really
you're the straw that stirs the drink.
And if there wasn't that entrance or or
that interest and commitment to this
side of town, we wouldn't even
we wouldn't be here today.
Um the last thing I want to point out um
why I'm I'm very supportive of this
particular ordinance um not just because
I've supported the Reed Avenue corridor
project from its inception was is
section two
in the ordinance.
And the last sentence in section two
says,
"No funds shall be expended from this
commitment until a final agreement with
Burlington Northern Santa Fe Railroad
has been reached."
So, I hope that
um relieves any concerns that colleagues
of mine on council might have because it
it's
it says that until we get that written
permission
from BNSF,
then we would not allocate the funds for
it. So, it it really does say, "Yeah, we
we want to commit these funds to the
project. We want to see the project move
forward. However,
we we do know that we need to get that
final approval first before we do so."
And um
so, I'm very supportive of this. We've
come a long way. There's been a lot of
work. Kudos to DHM and particularly to
our staff who've really never given up
and to my colleagues on council who've
never given up either.
Councilman Moody.
Uh thank you, Mr. Chair, and through
you. Thank you for your public comment,
everybody. I understand there was some
approved in 2017, but however, a lot can
change in nearly a decade.
Um one thing that concerned me was the
BNSF Railroad talking about wanting more
industrial usage. Doesn't have to be
warehouses. It can be even just
large-scale aspects there.
And then also, I know gentrification may
not happen now, but that can happen
10-15 years. And I know this as a
geographer. I actually tell my students
this just 5 weeks ago. So, again, it
happens over a long term. So, you got to
look at it from a long-term perspective,
not short-term. And then finally, the
Wyoming Tribune Eagle I'm looking at
right now. Have it right here in front
of me. And for the public, you can just
go Tribune Eagle opinion poll on Google.
Um it asked do you support proposal by
Cheyenne City Council to use 5 million
from its more than 77 million general
fund reserves begin work in Reed Avenue
real quarter project 59.6 no, 40.4 yes.
So,
there's really not that much support in
the public now. So, that's why it'll be
a no vote. I'm doing it based on poll
and what constituents have told me.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Councilman Wolf. Um thank you very much,
Mr. Chairman. Um
I too, through you, I would I I too
would like to echo the the comments of
uh
the congratulations to the investors um
and uh
uh when I was uh came on the council on
November 24th, um this is the first
project I plunged into and
um and went over to um
Mr. Westby's and and um Brandon's uh
fine establishment and and talked and
met all of the people including Mr.
Lucero at the time and
and um and uh
you know, there were a lot of
there was a lot of hope, but also a lot
of concern. I mean, I have right in
front of me the Reed Avenue corridor
master plan
dated April 2018.
Um so,
uh
you know, there's been a lot of work
done on this, but what is I think
amazing
is how much all of this has coalesced
within the short time that I've now been
on the council.
Um and so, I'm fully supportive of this.
I would also want to just um note that
uh we received a strong letter from the
um
uh DDA
uh this morning uh and um really
appreciate that and appreciate their
support. And again, I'd I'd expressed my
support to the mayor and the chief of
staff and um and of course to um
uh Director Cobb and all the work that
uh has gone on um through that. So,
um I'm not a big believer of polls
conducted by um newspapers.
Uh I think um
that I will just reflect that most
people couldn't even find Reed Avenue
with the help of Google Maps. Um and uh
so we've got a lot of work to do to
educate the populace about it. Um but uh
we put this uh we took this did not put
this on the six-penny ballot for some
very, very good reasons.
Um but I'm uh delighted that we're
taking this action and moving forward
with it. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Thank you. Uh
My comment is I I remember when I was
still working for the railroad and I was
representing my fellow employees
uh when the city was trying to um
uh make a land exchange with 12 parking
spots for my fellow employees. That was
right in front of the depot because the
city wanted to put a plaza
in front of the depot.
I see those same
fellow employees of mine that are there
now on Fridays on the plaza telling me,
"Wow, this is really great.
I'm glad we gave up those 12 parking
places."
So, uh
you know, as leaders we have to have
vision.
And I think by putting our money where
our mouth is is going to show the
railroad our commitment as well.
With that, all in favor signify by
saying aye.
Aye. Aye. Those no.
The recommendation of the Finance
Committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to approve on
second reading with Councilman Moody
voting no. Next item. Number 23A,
drainage easement agreement between the
City of Cheyenne and CBH Properties
Cheyenne LLC for a recently constructed
stormwater detention pond.
Staff report.
Uh
Chairman, through you. Aaron Gates, city
staff engineer.
Uh this is a drainage easement agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and CBH
Properties
for a new stormwater detention pond at
uh what is now address 3906 East
Pershing.
This is the recently constructed
Christian Brothers Automotive.
Uh
staff uh has reviewed the agreement.
Uh it allows for the city to enter the
property for any emergency maintenance
and verify that the facilities have been
constructed and are maintained as
appropriate. I stand for any questions.
Any questions from committee for Ms.
Gates?
Go to public comment.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, can I have a motion? Mr.
Chairman, I move to approve. Second.
Been moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman White. White, any further
discussion?
All in favor, signify by saying I. I.
>> I.
Are there noes?
One opposed, the recommendation of the
Finance Committee at the next meeting of
the governing body will will be to
approve. Next item.
Number 23B, drainage easement agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and Tractor
Supply Company for a recently
constructed stormwater detention pond.
Staff report.
Chairman, through you. Aaron Gates, city
staff engineer. This is a drainage
easement agreement between the city and
Tractor Supply on Hutchins Drive. Uh
again, similar document and language
that allows the city to verify that the
improvements have been constructed and
will be maintained. I stand for any
questions.
Comments or questions from the committee
for Ms. Gates?
Um any further public comment?
Anyone in the room? Anyone online?
Going to get a motion.
Mr. Chairman, I move to approve. Second.
Then moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman Wright. Any further
comments or questions?
All those in favor, signify by saying I.
I.
No opposed. So, the recommendation of
the Finance Committee at the next
meeting of the governing body will be to
approve.
Next item, please. Number 23C,
Professional Services Agreement between
the City of Cheyenne and McGee, Hearne &
Piles LLP doing business as MHP
Assurance Services LLP for auditing the
annual financial statements of the City
of Cheyenne, Wyoming City of Cheyenne,
Wyoming and its Board of Public
Utilities.
Staff report.
Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman, members of
the Finance Committee. My name is Robin
Lockman and I'm the City Treasurer.
Before you is a professional services
agreement between the city, the Board of
Public Utilities, and MHP Assurance
Services LLP to perform our annual
financial and compliance audits for
fiscal years 26,
27, and 28.
This agreement is the result of a formal
request for proposal process conducted
earlier this year.
After evaluating four proposals, the
evaluation committee again selected MHP
as the most qualified firm to serve the
city's needs.
The total not to exceed amount for both
entities for this three-year period is
$548,600.
The city's specific portion is capped at
$352,800.
To provide context on the annual costs
and the stabilization that we have
achieved through this RFP, the breakdown
is uh as as follows by fiscal year.
Fiscal year 26 is $113,600.
Fiscal year 27 is $117,100.
And fiscal year 28 is 122,100.
Bow Pugh's share for this 3-year term is
capped at 195,800.
I want to emphasize why continuing our
partnership with MHP is beneficial for
the city.
First, this will provide market
stability. Due to the persistent
shortage of accountants nationally, many
municipalities are currently struggling
to secure any qualified CPA firms to do
their audits.
By moving back to a multi-year contract,
we have secured a commitment locked in
predictable predictable rates.
Second, MHP is a local firm with deep
roots in our community, which aligns
with our preference for supporting local
professional services.
And finally, third, MHP possesses
invaluable institutional knowledge from
years of auditing the city.
Because they already understand our
complex financial structures and
software, we avoid the learning curve
associated with the new firm.
This will save the city significant
amount of staff time.
Uh Stephanie Pickering, partner MHP,
should be on Zoom in attendance, and I'm
happy to answer any questions as well.
Thank you.
Questions or comments from the committee
for Madam Treasurer? Just one quick
question. Councilor Moody, go ahead.
My name is Chairman Theriault. Uh thank
you, ma'am. Uh will this also audit any
of the federal and state grants as well?
Mr. Chairman, through you, yes, it is
the federal grants.
All right. Thank Thank you so much. I
just wanted the public to be aware of
that.
Any further questions or comments from
the committee?
We'll go to public comment. Any public
comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
Um Mr. Chairman, I would uh move to
approve the
contract um and um total amount not to
exceed $548,600.
Second.
It's been moved by Councilman Wolf
second by Councilman White any further
comments or questions. Mr. Wolf,
Councilman Moody go ahead. Thank you Mr.
Chairman through you.
Again uh this is very important uh for
the public as you know we're now we're
auditing say how your money's spent but
also the grants from federal and state
dollars is that's your money as well
too. So glad that we're doing this and
we have a multi-year contract. Thank you
Mr. Chairman.
Councilman Wolf do you have a comment?
Um Mr. Chairman I would
Councilman Moody's uh comments uh
I've actually read the whole fiscal
report. Um I um I really compliment uh
uh
Director Lochman and and her staff. Um
it's a it's a very very complimentary of
uh their work. Um and it's also
absolutely as Councilman Moody points
out essential to
the public's trust in what the city does
and what the city council uh
um gets to um
uh review and um and uh MHP is a superb
organization. We are really really lucky
that they're
willing to continue to do this and to do
it on a three-year contract and
so I'm delighted to vote to approve
this. Thank you.
Seeing no further comments or questions
all those in favor signify by saying I.
Seeing there's none opposed the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item.
Number 25A consideration to purchase
between the city of Cheyenne and Fuel
Management Solutions Incorporated for
fuel site pump upgrades at the Prairie
View Golf Course and Airport Golf
Course.
Staff report.
Good day Chairman committee members.
This contract will with fuel management
solutions will upgrade the tanks and
replace them as well as the controllers
to bring them into a card reader instead
of the paper and pin.
Uh at the four and that'll bring it up
to work with our other four sites that
we have currently using the system.
And at the Prairie View Golf Course, the
total amount of $64,808.18.
And at the Airport Golf Course, the
upgrades will cost $67,036.18
for a grand total of $131,000
$844.36.
And I recommend approval.
Any comments or questions from committee
for staff?
Councilman Moody. Yes, through you. Uh
thank you, sir. So, this one will go to
the card reader. Are all Are all of our
pumps now, after this is approved, have
card readers instead of pen and paper?
Uh through you, Chairman. This will
bring
these two in compliant with the other
four. There'll be one left that will
still need to be upgraded and that's at
the cemetery. Um that is requiring new
tanks. It's a little bit more
complicated. So, probably all but one
will be on the card reader.
Thank you.
Any further questions?
We'll go to public comment in the room.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion? Second.
Chairman, I move to approve an amount
not to exceed $131,844.36.
Second. It's been moved by Councilman
Moody, second by Councilman Wolf. Any
further comments or questions?
All in favor signify by saying I.
Seeing there's none opposed, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item.
Number 26e, designation of the official
voting delegate and alternate delegate
for the city of Cheyenne at the June
4th, 2026 Wyoming Association of
Municipalities Summer Convention
business meeting to be held in Laramie,
Wyoming. Staff report.
Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
for the record I'm Mayor Patrick
Collins.
Uh every year the Wyoming Association of
Municipalities holds their annual
meeting. This year it'll be in Laramie
and as part of that sometimes we get to
vote and each community is given one
official voting delegate. Historically
that has been Dr. Mark Rinne. He's a
member of their Board of Directors. He
manages or is the chairman of their
legislative leadership committee and he
would like to do that again this year.
Uh as the alternate for the last 5 years
I've been the alternate. Unfortunately
Mr. Rinne always shows up and votes so
I've never had to to exercise that but
that would be the recommendation is Dr.
Rinne to be the
member for the city of Cheyenne and I'll
be there and can back him up in fact if
he's not able to vote.
Any comments or questions from the
committee for Mr. Mayor?
Councilman Moody. Thank you Mr. Mayor
through you. I thank you Mr. Mayor.
Could there be a potential conflict with
Dr. Rinne considering the one position
he's going for
after council could this be sort of
conflict of interest?
Mr. Mayor. Mr. Chairman through you. I
don't think so but
I think these municipal issues that
we're talking about are are
non-controversial. Um
I guess that would be a decision this
body would have to make.
Any further comments or questions?
Any public comment on this?
Any public comment online?
Can I get a motion?
Mr. Chair, I move to designate
Councilman Rinne as the official voting
delegate and Mayor Collins as the
alternate delegate. Second.
It's been moved by Councilman seconded
by
Councilman Wolf.
Any further discussion? Uh Mr. Chair, I
I would just state that um
while my colleague from Ward 3 uh brings
up a a good question, I see no con-
potential conflict here uh considering
that the fact that um this uh
summer business meeting for WAM takes
place in on June 4th
and uh
quite some time before the uh primary a
couple months later in in
in my experience, the issues discussed
at both the summer and winter meetings
are strictly municipal-related
and um
don't necessarily um
draw into uh some of the controversies
that some of the state issues may have.
So, I'll I'll be supporting this today.
Councilman Moody? Yep. Uh thank you, Mr.
Chairman, through you. I'll just do an
abstain just because I do want more
information and to rest assured there
will be no conflict of interest. So,
it's not an aye or nay, it's an
abstention that is allowed Roberts Rules
of Order. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Okay, all those in favor signify by
saying aye.
Aye.
And abstained.
Okay.
The recommendation of the Finance
Committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be
to appoint Dr. Rennie as the official
voting delegate and Mayor Collins as the
alternate delegate
with uh Councilman Moody abstaining.
Next item, we have another item on our
agenda.
Uh with that, uh Madam Clerk.
Contract modification number one to
contract number 8169 between the City of
Cheyenne and JTL Group Incorporated
doing business as Knife River for the
2025 City Overlay number one project.
Staff report.
Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman and members
of the committee. Uh Doug Clown, city
construction manager.
Uh first off, I want to thank you for
the opportunity to bring this forward in
this manner. Uh we're here because I
quite frankly, didn't do my job. So, a
little bit behind, but I need to get
this done.
Uh the modification before you today is
for an extension of the city overlay
number one from um
on Cheshire Drive.
There was a quest a request by the
Street and Alley division that we fill a
gap that was going to be left um between
their project on Concord
and Pershing and a section of Concord
from Newton to Andover.
Anyway,
that is an addition of approximately 435
center line miles of roadway, which
includes concrete sidewalk, curb,
gutter, valley pan, um repairs and also
asphalt paving.
Um
Staff has reviewed this contract
modification and it is our
recommendation that we move forward with
approval.
And I will stand for questions.
I'll open this for questions from the
committee for staff.
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment.
No public comment in the room. How about
online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
Mr. Chair, I move to approve in an
amount not to exceed $217,150.20.
Second.
It's moved by Councilman Wright, second
by Councilman Wolf. Any further comments
or questions?
Seeing none, all in favor signify by
saying aye.
And seeing there's no opposed, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve.
Seeing there's no further business in
front of the Finance Committee, we are
adjourned.